## Ren Burnett

Adaptable fullstack developer with attention to detail and the ability to empathetically and thoughtfully collaborate. Excited to bring traits gained in six years as a precision technician to help shape quality code. Enthusiastic about learning new technologies/languages as well as developing helpful, practical software.

(206) 669-7498
renardburnett@gmail.com
github.com/renburnett
linkedin.com/in/renard-burnett-ii
renburnett.com

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Grasher** — Food Inventory Tracker

grasher-food-tracker-frontend.herokuapp.com
github.com/renburnett/grasher-app-frontend

- React frontend, Ruby Rails backend, Semantic-React UI for styling
- Login: r@r.com Pass: 123

#### **Kexp Song Favoriter** — *Track User's Favorite Songs*

kexp-song-favoriter-rails.herokuapp.com github.com/renburnett/kexp song favoriter

- Static web app implemented with Ruby on Rails
- Queries KEXP endpoint
- Persists songs and users to Postgres DB

# **Chatter** — *ChatRoom WebApp* github.com/kel29/chat-frontend

github.com/kel29/chat-server

- React frontend, Rails API backend
- ActionCables and React ActionCable Provider to handle connections
- Bootstrap used for styling

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Banana App (BGP), React and Rails Developer — Seattle <a href="mailto:github.com/FoodIsLifeBGP/banana-rn">github.com/FoodIsLifeBGP/banana-rn</a> banana app

JANUARY 2020 - CURRENT

• React Native frontend written in TypeScript, Rails backend

Currently contributing to Banana App code base. Banana App is an open-source, not-for-profit project of The Be Good Foundation. Aim is to reduce hunger by simplifying the food donation process.

### **Microsoft via WTIA**, Software Developer Apprentice — Redmond

NOVEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018

Created a Bluetooth Radio Provisioning tool that is now used to set up mock peripherals for testing against the Windows OS for Bluetooth Quality Team. Reduced the time spent testing OS by one to two hours. Wrote a Python script that ran daily to scrape customer reviews from online stores; data was made actionable after it was visualized in PowerBI. During my time here, began teaching myself React. Enjoyed learning from teammates and problem solving alongside them.

### **Boeing**, Composite Technician and Team Lead — Everett

MARCH 2011 - APRIL 2017

Team leader of a fast-paced seven person Composite Repair Team. Interactions with teammates were professional, respectful and fun. Ensured that majority of deadlines were met but not at the expense of quality work.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript / ES6
React / React Native
HTML5 / CSS
Git
C#
Python
Ruby on Rails
MVC Architecture
SQL
Azure

#### **EDUCATION**

# Flatiron School — Software Engineering Certificate

AUGUST 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

- Functional and Object Oriented Programming with JavaScript and Ruby.
- Learned to design and create single page web applications from scratch using MVC architecture.
- Worked with string, array, object data structures and algorithms to solve code challenges with vanilla JavaScript.

### North Seattle College

JUNE 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2024

# **TLG Learning** — C# Developer Certificate

SEPTEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2017

 Learned how to leverage concepts such as inheritance, method overriding, interfaces, and object hierarchies in C#.